cloggs.co.uk 2016-06-29

# Privacy at Cloggs

## Customer Protection

We are committed to protecting your privacy. We will only use information given at the time of ordering or when making an enquiry by whatever means is collected lawfully and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. It is collected by Senior Cloggs personnel and all transactions that you initiate with Cloggs.co.uk on this web site are confidential. We will never collect sensitive information about you without your explicit consent.

## Your Personal Information

We collect information about you for three main reasons:

  * i) To process your order,
  * ii) To make available the products and services you want, and
  * iii) To provide you with the most efficient and effective service possible. 

We will use the information you provide to enable us to process your orders and to provide you with the services and information offered through our website and which you request.

The type of information we will collect about you includes:- your name, your address, your shoe size, your e-mail address, your age, your phone number and your sex. Please note that some of these fields are optional.

Further, we will use the information you provide to:

  * \- Administer your account with us;
  * \- Verify and carry out financial transactions in relation to payments;
  * \- Improve the layout and/or content of the pages of our website and customise them for users;
  * \- Identify visitors to our website;
  * \- Carry out research on our users' demographics and tracking of sales data;
  * \- With your consent upon registering with us, send you information we think you may find useful or which you have requested from us, including information about our products and services (or those of carefully selected third parties), provided you have indicated that you do not object to being contacted for these purposes.
  * \- On occasion, we will share the information you have provided us with other companies within the _JD Sports Group_.

Subject to obtaining your consent we may contact you by telephone or text on the telephone numbers you have provided or by email with details of other products, and services or competitions or charitable fundraising. If you prefer not to receive any marketing communications from us, you can opt out at any time.

At any stage you also have the right to ask us to stop using your personal data for direct marketing purposes. You can opt-out any time by emailing our customer service team at customerservices@cloggs.co.uk; or by following the instructions _here_

## Controlling Your Personal Information

The website is owned by Cloggs (UK) Limited and the Data Controller is Venda

The data controller is responsible for and controls the processing of your personal data in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998. We are registered with the Information Commissioner's Office and our registration number is 01422012.

We aim for the information we hold about you to be accurate and up to date. You can check the information that we hold about you by logging in to your account. If you find any inaccuracies you should delete or correct it promptly. The personal information will be held securely, in accordance with our internal security policy, The Data Protection Act 1998, Tier 1 PCI Compliance, and the law.

If you are concerned about your data, you have the right subject to payment of a small fee (currently £10) to request access the personal data which we may hold of process about you. 

You have the right to require us to correct any inaccuracies, block of delete your personal data free of charge.

Your personal data is forwarded to our couriers, either DX, Hermes or UK Mail, and is used to communicate with you throughout delivery. 

We will use the information you provide to send you information we think you may find useful or which you have requested from us, including information about our similar products and services, provided you have not objected to being contacted for these purposes.

If you do not want to hear about Cloggs product offers, sales or promotions that we believe you may be interested in can be removed from the offer list by sending an email to customerservices@cloggs.co.uk; or by following the instructions at _here_

**Data Protection:** we know that you care how the information about you is used an shared and we appreciate your trust in us to do that carefully and sensibly and in full compliance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

## Automatic Customer Tracking

We use technology to track the patterns of behaviour of our visitors to our site and e-mail communications so that we can provide relevant content and messaging, speed up the payment procedure for you, deliver the appropriate products and special offers to you, in the most easy to use and personalised way.

A cookie is a small amount of data sent from our server and stored on your computer's hard drive. We have several cookies which are essential to the operation of the site, they are strictly necessary for the sale of products requested by you. A list of such cookies can be found below:

SID | First page viewed | Contains information about the session. | Never  
---|---|---|---  
setViewPerPage | Product lists / search results | Records the user's preference for the number of products to view per page. | 1 week  
setView | Product lists / search results | Records the user's preference for how products are arranged on product list and search results pages. | 1 week  
setCurrency | During currency change | Records the user's currency preference so that exchange rates can be made. | 1 week  
RVI | Viewing products | Records the products the user has recently viewed to show in the "Recently Viewed Items" box. | 1 week  
RSI | Keyword search | Records the last 3 keyword searches so they appear in the "Recent Search Box", allowing the Customer to jump back to those searches quickly. | 1 day  
  
RFID

| Add to cart / log in | 

Records the user's unique user reference ID for the current session.

| Never  
referid | First page viewed | Referral data to track sites that link to Venda. | 2 days  
quench | All | For managing performance. | End of session  
newCurr | During currency change | Records the user's currency preference so that exchange rates can be made. | 1 week  
locn | All | Records the user's location (region) preference. | Never  
lang | All | Records the user's language preference. | Never  
httprefer | First page viewed | Referral data to track sites that link to Venda. | 2 days  
device | First page viewed | Stores the device preference. | End of session  
  
We also use Cookies to enhance the structure of site and, as such, your experience whilst on Cloggs.co.uk. We use cookies to establish who has seen our adverts and visited our site. Details of these style of Cookies can be found below:

Company | Host | Description | Duration  
---|---|---|---  
MyThings | 3rd Party | Used to create personalised banner advertising after you have left our site. For more information click the "i" on the banners. | Up to 30 days  
Quantcast | 3rd Party | Generates information about consumer behaviour in order to serve relevant advertising to other potential customers. | Up to 90 days  
Affiliate Window | 3rd Party | These cookies provide information on who directed you to our site. Occasionally we may reward these referers.  | Up to 30 days  
  
We also use Facebook and Google Analytics, which are detailed below:

Cloggs.co.uk uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including your IP address) will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States . Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing other services relating to website activity and internet usage. Google may also transfer this information to third parties where required to do so by law, or where such third parties process the information on Google's behalf. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google in the manner and for the purposes set out above.

If you’re logged in to Facebook and visit Cloggs.co.uk which has the Like button, your browser sends Facebook information about your visit. It’s important to note that Facebook is not retrieving this information. Rather, since the Like button is a little piece of Facebook embedded on Cloggs.co.uk, the browser is sending information about the request to load Facebook content on that page. Facebook record some of this information for a limited amount of time to help show you a personalized experience on Cloggs.co.uk and to improve our products. For example, when you go to a product page on Cloggs.co.uk with a Like button, Facebook need to know who you are in order to show you what your Facebook friends have liked on Cloggs.co.uk. The data Facebook receive includes your user ID, the website you're visiting, the date and time, and other browser-related information.

Regardless of whether you are logged in or not, Facebook do not use the information we receive when you visit Cloggs.co.uk to create a profile of your browsing behavior on third-party sites or to show you ads, although Facebook may use anonymous or aggregate data to improve ads generally. Facebook delete or anonymise the information they receive within 90 days, and they don't sell it to advertisers or share it without your permission.

If you have any questions/comments about privacy, please feel free to contact us at customerservices@cloggs.co.uk or in writing at the above address, for more information.
